Guide to the Schieffelin Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Second Generation, 1779-1877; Series II
  - JACOB SCHIEFFELIN, JR. 1793-1880
    - Correspondence, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, 1833 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence, 1834 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence, 1835 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence, 1837 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence, 1838 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence, 1839 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence, 1843-44 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence, 1845 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence, 1846-47 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, 1848-49 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence, 1851-52 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence, 1853-54 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, 1860-63 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence, 1877 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Empty envelopes, 1859-60, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Military papers, 1812-25 (microfilm), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Survey book, 1828-48 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Survey book, papers found inside, 1834, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - RICHARD LAWRENCE SCHIEFFELIN, 1801-1889
    - Newspaper article, 1878 (photocopy), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - W. H. SCHIEFFELIN & CO.
    See: H. H. Schieffelin & Co.
- Third Generation, 1844-1992; Series III
  Series III contains papers regarding the children of Jacob Schieffelin, Jr.; material is subdivided under their names, arranged alphabetically. Within each subgroup, the material is arranged alphabetically by folder title and then chronologically.
  - CLINTON EMANUEL D. SCHIEFFELIN, 1823-1884
    - Agreement, 1845 Feb 3 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Correspondence, 1844 May 18 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Correspondence, 1853 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Correspondence, 1854 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Correspondence, 1855 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Correspondence, 1856 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Correspondence, 1857 Feb 16 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Correspondence, 1858 Oct (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Correspondence, 1860 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Empty envelopes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Newspaper clippings from 1852 (overland journey to Oregon) and 1884 (his death) (photocopies), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - The Oregon Sentinel of Jacksonville
      - Article on gold at Rogue River, 1860 Jan 21 (photocopy), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 77)
      - Issue, vol. IX, no. 39
        See: Oversize, Box 9, folder 133
  - EDWARD GIRARD SCHIEFFELIN, 1836-1922
    - Agreement, 1883 Oct 22 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Checks, 1898-99 (Box 5, Folder 79-80)
    - Correspondence, 1863 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Correspondence, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Correspondence, 1887 Jun 27 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Correspondence, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Diary, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Military papers, 1861-65, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 86-90)
      See also: For papers from 1863-65, see microfilm, Box 4, folder 61; and see also Oversize, Box 9, folder 134
    - Receipt for telephone service, 1902 Jan 13 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - ELIZABETH SCHIEFFELIN, 1829-1901
    - Account books, 1881-89 (Box 6, Folder 92)
- Fourth Generation, 1836-1992; Series IV
  Series IV contains papers regarding Edward L. Schieffelin and Mary Schieffelin Brady. Under each name, the material is arranged alphabetically by folder title and then chronologically. A third subseries, Other Schieffelin Family Material, contains items which can not be associated with any one Schieffelin.
  - EDWARD L. SCHIEFFELIN, 1847-1897
    - Agreement, 1878 May 17 (photostat), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - "Ed Schieffelin's [1882] Trip to Alaska," by his brother (photostat of typescript), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 94)
      Original owned by the Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley. No reproduction permitted Contact the Bancroft Library if photocopy is desired.
    - "Edward Schieffelin," biography (typescript carbon), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - "History of the Discovery of Tombstone, Arizona, as told by the Discoverer, Edward Schieffelin," (photostat of typescript), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - The Mining Record: a weekly newspaper (New York, N.Y.), 1879 Apr 26 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Newspaper articles (one photocopy), 1879, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 98)
      See also: Oversize, Box 9, folder 135
    - Postcards and stamps portraying E. L. and his grave (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - "Report upon the Property belonging to the Tombstone Mill and Mining Co., Pima County, Arizona," by Julius H. Striedinger, 1879 Oct 26 (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Reproduced photograph, "Alaska Prospecting Party" portraying Effingham and Edward L. Schieffelin and others (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - "Simple Monument of Granite over Pioneer's Grave," description of Edward's grave (carbon typescript), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - "The Tombstone District," Bullion - Supplement (New York, N.Y.), 1879 Sep 1 (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - MARY SCHIEFFELIN BRADY
    - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, 1929-38
      See: Oversize, Box 9, folder 136
    - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 104)
      Consists of: Geology and Ore Deposits of the Tombstone District, Arizona
    - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, post 1945-47 (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, 1950, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, 1956-57 (Box 6, Folder 107)
      See also: Oversize, Box 9, folder 137
    - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, 1959-66 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      See also: Oversize, Box 9, folders 138-140
    - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone (Box 6, Folder 109)
      See also: Oversize Box 8, folder 141
    - Articles, pamphlets regarding Oregon, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Correspondence, 1959, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Correspondence, 1964 Jun 1-9 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Correspondence, 1964 Jun 11 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Correspondence, 1964 Aug-Oct (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Correspondence, 1965 Jul 24 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - OTHER SCHIEFFELIN FAMILY MATERIAL
    - Genealogical charts
      See: Oversize, Box 9, folder 142
    - Paper money, 1779, 1862-63 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Peter Parley's Almanac for Old and Young, 1836 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Miscellaneous papers
      See: Oversize, Box 9, folder 143
- Schieffelin Associates, 1843-1862; Series V
  This series contains papers relating to John W. Guernsey and Denison A. Lockwood, who may have been business associates of Jacob Jr.
  - JOHN W. GUERNSEY
    - Agreement, deeds, receipts, etc., 1843 May 2 (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - Agreements, deeds, receipts, etc., 1858 (Box 7, Folder 121)
    - Agreements, deeds, receipts, etc., 1861-62 (Box 7, Folder 122)
  - DENISON A. LOCKWOOD, B. 1811
    - Diary of a voyage to California, 1849 Feb-May (Box 7, Folder 123)
    - Papers found in diary of 1849 Feb - May (Box 7, Folder 124)
    - Diary of a voyage to and from California, 1849-50 (Box 7, Folder 125)
- Oversize
  Oversize (Boxes 8-9) contains material from Series I-IV. The arrangement, based on the size of the material, parallels the order of the collection.
  - SERIES I. FIRST GENERATION
    - Jacob Schieffelin, 1757-1835
      - Agreements, deeds, receipts, etc., 1796 Nov 19 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - Agreements, deeds, receipts, etc., 1803 Apr 6 (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - SERIES II. SECOND GENERATION
    - H. H. Schieffelin & Co.
      - Newspaper article, 1879 Nov (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - Jacob Schieffelin, Jr. 1793-1880
      - Agreements, deeds, receipts, etc., 1813-19 (Box 8, Folder 129)
      - Agreements, deeds, receipts, etc., 1827 (Box 8, Folder 130)
      - Agreements, deeds, receipts, etc., 1835-37 (Box 8, Folder 131)
      - Agreements, deeds, receipts, etc., 1854 (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - SERIES III. THIRD GENERATION
    - Clinton Emanuel D. Schieffelin, 1823-1884
      - The Oregon Sentinel of Jacksonville, vol. IX, no. 39, 1864 Oct 15 (Box 9, Folder 133)
    - Edward Girard Schieffelin, 1836-1922
      - Military papers, 1862-64 (Box 9, Folder 134)
  - SERIES IV. FOURTH GENERATION
    - Edward L. Schieffelin, 1847-1897
      - Newspaper articles (one photocopy), 1879, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 135)
    - Mary Schieffelin Brady
      - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, 1929-38 (Box 9, Folder 136)
      - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 137)
      - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 138)
      - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 139)
      - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 140)
      - Articles, pamphlets, postcards and other publications regarding Tombstone (Box 9, Folder 141)
    - Other Schieffelin Family Material
      - Genealogical charts, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 142)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1823-73 (Box 9, Folder 143)